Guide to the Assistant Comptroller for Estates, Trusts and Taxes, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Assistant comptroller for estates, trusts and taxes, Yale University, records
1740-2007
RU 544
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
57.5
The records consist of reports, subject files, agreements, tax and audit files, financial statements, and memoranda documenting the operations of the assistant comptroller for estates, trusts and taxes at Yale.
Yale University. Office of Finance and Administration
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 5-B (YRG 5-B), Accounting records and records of the Yale comptroller.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted to the office of origin only.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of reports, subject files, agreements, tax and audit files, financial statements, and memoranda documenting the operations of the assistant comptroller for estates, trusts and taxes at Yale.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by accession.
Universities and colleges -- Finance; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Benefactors; Yale University -- Finance; Yale University. Office of Finance and Administration
- Records concerning the estates of Olivia C. Hotchkiss and George E. Day, 1905-1909; Accession 1979-A-021
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted to office of origin only
- Tax returns, 1974-1982; Accession 1983-A-079
- Materials transferred out of previous audit accessions, circa 1946-1980; Accession 1983-A-116
  - Yale University
- Records, 1971-1984; Accession 1985-A-037
  - Yale University Information Return - Form 990, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Wills, 1891-1962; Accession 1985-A-038
- Records, 1980-1983; Accession 1985-A-039
- Tax forms, 1976-1984; Accession 1986-A-095
- Records, 1972-1986; Accession 1988-A-033
- Records, 1720-1977; Accession 1988-A-036
- Estate records, 1930-1983 (bulk 1973-1983); Accession 1988-A-048
- Records, 1966-1987; Accession 1988-A-093
- Records, 1972-1987; Accession 1989-A-109
- Tax Department records, 2001-2007; Accession 2009-A-097
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2043
  - Drama Productions, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Yale Southern Observatory, Inc. (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Yale Alumni Publications, Inc. (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Yale University - State of Arizona (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Yale University - State of California (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Yale University - State of Colorado (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Yale University - State of Connecticut (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Yale University - State of Illinois (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Yale University - State of Indiana (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Yale University - State of New Jersey (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Yale University - State of Louisiana (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Yale University - State of Maine (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Yale University - State of Maryland (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Yale University - State of Minnesota (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Yale University - State of Missouri (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Yale University - State of Nevada (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Yale University - State of New Mexico (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Yale University - State of New York (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Yale University - State of North Carolina (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Yale University - State of Pennsylvania (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - Yale University - State of South Carolina (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - Yale University - State of Texas (Box 6, Folder 81)
  - Yale University - Various States (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - Yale University - State of Virginia (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - Yale University - State of Wisconsin (Box 6, Folder 84)
  - Yale University 2004 Form 990-T - 1 of 2, FYE 6/30/05 (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - Yale University 2004 Form 990-T - 2 of 2, FYE 6/30/05 (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - Yale University 2005 Form 990-T - 1 of 2, FYE 6/30/06 (Box 7, Folder 87)
  - Yale University 2005 Form 990-T - 2 of 2, FYE 6/30/05 (Box 7, Folder 88)
  - Yale University 2006 Form 990-T - 1 of 2, FYE 6/30/07 (Box 7, Folder 89)
  - Yale University 2006 Form 990-T - 2 of 2, FYE 6/30/07 (Box 7, Folder 90)